A Guide to the Correspondence and Subject files of the Virginia Office of the Secretary of Commerce and Resources, 1972-1986
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Secretary of Commerce and Resources Correspondence and Subject files, 1972-1986
The Library of Virginia
32041, 32269, 32511, 32673, 32726, 33372, 37780
112 cu. ft. (112 boxes)
Virginia. Secretary of Commerce and Resources.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Secretary of Commerce and Resources, 6 March 1984 [Accession 32041].
Transferred from the Secretary of Commerce and Resources, 26 December 1984 [Accession 32269].
Transferred from the Secretary of Commerce and Resources, 25 September 1985 [Accession 32511].
Transferred from the Secretary of Commerce and Resources, 27 February 1986 [Accession 32673].
Transferred from the Secretary of Commerce and Resources, 16 May 1986 [Accession 32726].
Transferred from the Secretary of Commerce and Resources, 19 January 1989 [Accession 33372].
Transferred from the Secretary of Commerce and Resources, Unknown date [Accession 37780].
Biographical Information
Under the Code, Title 2.1, Chapter 5.1, the Secretary of Commerce and Resources is responsible for assisting the Governor in implementing policies for the conservation and use of natural resources, for promoting economic development, providing managerial guidance and direction to Commerce and Resources agencies, and developing and promoting Commerce and Resources programs and budgets. In 1986 this secretariat was dissolved and split into two separate offices, the Secretary of Economic Development and the Secretary of Natural Resources. In 1994 the name of the office of the Secretary of Economic Development was changed to the Secretary of Commerce and Trade.
Scope and Content
Correspondence and subject files, 1972-1986, of the Secretary of Commerce and Resources. The correspondence documents the development, establishment and implementation of policies and procedures on behalf of the Governor implementing the Secretary's mandate. The records consist of incoming and outgoing correspondence, reports, memoranda, budget documents and related materials. The collection is arranged into seven series by accession number. For later records see Secretary of Natural Resources and Secretary of Commerce and Trade.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Correspondence and subject files, 1985-1986 [Accession 33372]
Series II: Correspondence and subject files, 1984 [Accession 32726]
Series III: Correspondence and subject files, 1972-1981 [Accession 32041]
Series IV: Correspondence and subject files, 1980-1984 [Accession 32269]
Series V: Correspondence and subject files, 1982-1983 [Accession 32511]
Series VI: Correspondence and subject files, 1984 [Accession 32673]
Series VII: Correspondence and subject files, 1972-1980 [Accession 37780]
Contents List
- Series I: Correspondence and subject files, [Accession 33372], 1986-1994, Extent: 11 cu. ft. (11 boxes). (Box 1-11)
  - Agriculture and Consumer Services, General, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Agricultural Products Commission, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Animal Health, Division of, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Avian Flu, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Consumer Affairs Office, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Coyote problems in Virginia, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Farm situation in Virginia, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Drought, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Goat's milk, Sale and distribution of, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - International Trade, Division of, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - JLARC Study on Seafood, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Legislative proposals (Agriculture), 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Legislative proposals (Agri-Wine liter tax), 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Plant Protection and Pesticide Regulation Bureau, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Rural Virginia Development Foundation, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - State Fair of Virginia, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Turfgrass regulations, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - We Have it Made in Virginia, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Wineries in Virginia, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Air Pollution Control Board, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Acid Rain, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Accountancy, Board of, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Commerce, Dept. of, General, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Commerce, Review of existing regulations, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Athletic Commission, Virginia, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Contractors, Board of, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Fair Housing Law (HUD), 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Legislative proposals, Commerce, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Real Estate Commission, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Caledon State Park, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - False Cape State Park, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Forestry, State Division of, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Historic Resources, Division of, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Conservation and Historic Resources, General, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - EPA (Air Board), 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Legislative proposals, Gunston Hall, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Legislative proposals, Historic Landmarks, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Legislative proposals, Soil and Water Committee, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Litter control, Division of, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Non point Source Pollution, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Parks, Division of, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Railroad Right Of Way, Galax, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Smith Mountain Lake, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Smith Mountain Lake Campground, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Soil and Water Conservation Commission, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Yorktown, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Economic Development, Dept. of, General, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Legislative proposals, Industrial Development, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - International Marketing, Dept. of, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - Industrial Directory, 16th edition, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - Marketing, Division of, 1985 Jan-July (Box 4)
  - Marketing, Division of, 1985 July-Dec (Box 4)
  - Marketing, High Tech Consortium, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - Productivity Center, Virginia, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - Saturn Project, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - Science and Technology, Task Force, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - Small Business and Financial Services, Division of, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - Southern Center for International Studies, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - SPC, Leapfrog, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - SPC, CIT, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - SPC, General files, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - SPC, The Virginia Proposal, Binder I, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - SPC, The Virginia Proposal, Binder II, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - Trade Mission to Israel, etc., 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - Tourism, Division of, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Advertising info, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Blue Ridge Parkway, 50th Anniversary, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Hampton Roads, Future of, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Roanoke Transportation Museum, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Tourism and Travel Services, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Tourism, Search for director, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Tourism, Facts, Figures, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Employment Commission, Virginia, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Displaced workers, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Governor's Job Training Council, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Labor Market figures and reports, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Legislative proposals, VEC, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Self-Employment Opportunity Act, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Unemployment Insurance Claims, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Workmen's Compensation, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Chesapeake Bay, Progress report, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Chesapeake Bay, General, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Chesapeake Bay, Initiatives, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Coastal Resource Management, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Corps of Engineers, U.S. Army, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Daminozide (fruit-preserving pesticide), 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Dimilin-Gypsy moths, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Dredging proposals, U.S. Corps of Engineers, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Empress II, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Environment, Council on the, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Environmental Happenings in Virginia, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Environmental Happenings in Other States, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Environmental Impact Statements, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - EPA, General, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Hoskins Creek, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Hydrilla-Diquat, 1985-1986 (Box 7)
  - Kepone, 1985-1986 (Box 7)
  - Lake Gaston, Pipeline and other issues, 1985-1986 (Box 7)
  - Legislative proposals, Council on the Environment, 1985-1986 (Box 7)
  - Organotin (tributyltin-tbt), 1985-1986 (Box 7)
  - Shellfish Enhancement Task Force, 1985-1986 (Box 7)
  - Upper Roanoke River Valley Basin, 1985-1986 (Box 7)
  - Uranium Mining, 1985-1986 (Box 7)
  - Fish Passage Report on James River, 1985-1986 (Box 7)
  - Game and Inland Fisheries, General, 1985-1986 (Box 7)
  - ITT Microwave Tower, 1985-1986 (Box 7)
  - Legislative proposals, Game and Inland Fisheries, 1985-1986 (Box 7)
  - Appalachian Regional Commission, 1985-1986 (Box 7)
  - Community Development Block Grants, Notebooks, 1985-1986 (Box 8)
  - Community Block Grants, 1985-1986 (Box 8)
  - Delmarva Advisory Council, 1985-1986 (Box 8)
  - Director, Housing and Community Development, 1985-1986 (Box 8)
  - Fire Prevention Code, 1985-1986 (Box 8)
  - Housing and Community Development, General, 1985-1986 (Box 8)
  - Legislative proposal, HCD, 1985-1986 (Box 8)
  - Main Street Program, 1985-1986 (Box 8)
  - Housing for the Disabled, 1985-1986 (Box 8)
  - Private Sector Initiatives, 1985-1986 (Box 8)
  - Planning District Commissions, 1985-1986 (Box 8)
  - Regulations, HCD, 1985-1986 (Box 8)
  - Uniform Statewide Buildings Code, Drafts, 1985-1986 (Box 8)
  - Urban Enterprise Zones, 1985-1986 (Box 9)
  - Housing Development Authority, 1985-1986 (Box 9)
  - Legislative proposals, HDA, 1985-1986 (Box 9)
  - Labor and Industry, Dept of, 1985-1986 (Box 9)
  - Legislative proposals, DLI, 1985-1986 (Box 9)
  - Migrant and seasonal workers, 1985-1986 (Box 9)
  - OSHA (Federal) and VOSH (State), 1985-1986 (Box 9)
  - Right-to-work law, 1985-1986 (Box 9)
  - Legislative proposals, Marine Resources Commission, 1985-1986 (Box 9)
  - Sportfishing license, 1985-1986 (Box 9)
  - Marine Resources Commission, General, 1985-1986 (Box 9)
  - Striped bass moratorium, 1985-1986 (Box 9)
  - Virginia Institute of Marine Science, 1985-1986 (Box 9)
  - Milk Commission, Virginia, General, 1985-1986 (Box 9)
  - Coal news, 1985-1986 (Box 9)
  - Coal, Promotion of, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - Energy Services, Division of, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - Mine Safety Program, Women's Issues, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - Mined Land Reclamation, Division of, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - Mine Safety Program, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - Mines, Division of, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - Mines, Minerals, and Energy, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - Two-Acre Mining, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - United Mine Workers of America, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - Minority Business Enterprise, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - Back Bay, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - Dam Safety and Flood Control, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - Ground Water Issues, Contamination, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - Ohio River Basin Commission, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - Publications, State Water Control Board, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - Storage Tanks, Underground, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - EPA, Water Board, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - United Fiber glass plant, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - Water Control Board, State, General, 1985-1986 (Box 11)
  - Wastewater, Sewage Treatment Plan, 1985-1986 (Box 11)
  - Water and Sewage Assistance Authority, General, 1985-1986 (Box 11)
  - Low-level Nuclear Waste, 1985-1986 (Box 11)
  - Coal Surface Mining and Reclamation Regulations, Notebook, 1985-1986 (Box 11)
- Series II: Correspondence and subject files, 1984 [Accession 32726], 1984, Extent: 5 cu. ft. (5 boxes). (Box 11-15)
  - Potomac River Fisheries Commission, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Saltwater Fishing License Study Group, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Striped Bass Management, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Milk Commission, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Minority Business Enterprise, Office of, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Minority Business Enterprise, Minority Bank Deposits, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Minority Business Enterprise, Minority Business Procurement 1984 (Box 11)
  - Minority Business Enterprise, Office of, General, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Outdoors Foundation, Virginia, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Soil and Water Conservation Commission, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Tangier Island, Erosion situation, 1983-1984 (Box 11)
  - EPA and NPDES Permits, 1984 January-June (Box 11)
  - EPA and NPDES Permits, 1984 July-December (Box 11)
  - Groundwater Issues, RCRA and Uranium (also includes DuPont settlement), 1984 (Box 12)
  - Interbasin transfer of water (not Lake Gaston), 1984 (Box 12)
  - Wastewater and Sewage Treatment Plants, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Virginia-North Carolina water, Lake Gaston, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Hydrilla Problem, Water Control Board, 1984 (Box 12)
  - DHCD, Work plan for review of existing regulations, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Regulatory Review, Commerce, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Regulatory Review, Agriculture, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Regulatory Review, Labor and Industry, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Potomac River Basin (on the Interstate Commission), 1984 (Box 12)
  - Virginia-North Carolina Water Resources Management Agreement, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Virginia-Maryland Bi-State Agreement, 1984 (Box 12)
  - State Water Control Board, 1984 January-April (Box 12)
  - State Water Control Board, 1984 May-December (Box 12)
  - General Assembly, General, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Legislative Proposals for General Assembly Session, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Prompt Payment Act Reports, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Collegial Bodies Information, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Agency Head Retreat, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Cabinet Retreat, 1984 (Box 13)
  - State Comptroller's Office, 1984 (Box 13)
  - General Budget, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Budget Presentation on Chesapeake Bay, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Budget Presentation to House and Senate, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Personnel, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Capital Outlay, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Budget, Response to Delegate Ball's letter, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Building Security, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Cave Commission, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Bureau of Fiscal Services, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Internal Audit, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Dept. of Information Technology, 1984 (Box 13)
  - U.S. Dept. of Commerce, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Hazardous Waste Siting Board, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Applications and resumes for state government positions, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Regulatory reform, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Budget materials, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Memorandum, 1984 January-February (Box 14)
  - Memorandum, 1984 March-April (Box 14)
  - Memorandum, 1984 May-June (Box 14)
  - Memorandum, 1984 July-August (Box 14)
  - Memorandum, 1984 September-October (Box 14)
  - Memorandum, 1984 November-December (Box 14)
  - Dept. of General Services, 1984 (Box 14)
  - Private sector initiatives, 1984 (Box 14)
  - Science and Technology, Commission on, 1984 (Box 14)
  - Travel, Out of country approval, 1984 (Box 14)
  - Dept. of Planning and Budget, 1984 (Box 14)
  - Reorganization of State Government, 1984 (Box 14)
  - Resumes, 1984 (Box 14)
  - Wood as supplemental energy, 1984 (Box 14)
  - State Fair of Virginia, 1984 (Box 14)
  - Telecommunications, Dept. of, 1984 (Box 14)
  - Travel information, 1984 (Box 14)
  - United Way of Greater Richmond, 1984 (Box 14)
  - Virginia's Future, Commission on, 1984 (Box 14)
  - Applications, resumes for state government positions, 1984 (Box 14)
  - U.S. Savings Bond Campaign, 1984 (Box 14)
  - Virginia State Library, 1984 (Box 14)
  - Young ideas, 1984 (Box 14)
  - Inventory, 1984 (Box 14)
  - Financial statements, 1984 (Box 14)
  - Media, 1984 (Box 14)
  - David McCloud, Governor's Office, 1984 (Box 14)
  - Press releases, 1984 (Box 14)
  - Governor, 1984 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence from other state agencies, 1984 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, Misc., 1984 (Box 15)
  - Executive agreements, 1984 (Box 15)
  - Chesapeake Bay Agreement, 1984 (Box 15)
  - Personnel and Training, Dept. of, 1984 (Box 15)
  - Virginia Executive Institute, Dept. of Personnel and Training, 1984 (Box 15)
  - National Governor's Association, 1984 (Box 15)
  - Bureau of Fiscal Services, 1984 (Box 15)
  - Biographies of various persons, 1984 (Box 15)
  - Legislation, 1984 (Box 15)
  - Legislative services, 1984 (Box 15)
  - Legislators, State and Federal, 1984 (Box 15)
  - Virginia State Library, 1984 (Box 15)
  - Lt. Governor, 1984 (Box 15)
  - Main Street Center, 1984 (Box 15)
  - Management Analysis and Systems Development, 1984 (Box 15)
  - Attorney General's Office, 1984 (Box 15)
  - Secretary of the Commonwealth, 1984 (Box 15)
  - Regulatory Reform, 1984 (Box 15)
- Series III: Correspondence and subject files, 1972-1981 [Accession 32041], 1984, Extent: 40 cu. ft. (40 boxes). (Box 1-40)
  - A-E, 1972-1977 (Box 1-2)
  - A-E (Reports), 1972-1977 (Box 3)
  - Energy, 1972-1977 (Box 4)
  - E-W, 1972-1977 (Box 5)
  - O-W, 1972-1977 (Box 6-7)
  - Outer Continental Shelf Activities, 1972-1977 (Box 8)
  - Water Control Board, 1972-1977 (Box 9)
  - Appointment letters, 1972-1977 (Box 10)
  - A-C, 1978 (Box 11)
  - Cabinet Secretaries and Speeches, 1978 (Box 12)
  - C-G, 1978 (Box 13)
  - C-M, 1978 (Box 14)
  - E-G, 1978 (Box 15)
  - H-M, 1978 (Box 16)
  - M-W, 1978 (Box 17)
  - A-C, 1979 (Box 18)
  - Budget information, 1979 (Box 19)
  - C-E, 1979 (Box 20)
  - F-I, 1979 (Box 21)
  - J-N, 1979 (Box 22)
  - O-W, 1979 (Box 23)
  - Outer Continental Shelf Activities, 1979 (Box 24)
  - W, 1979 (Box 25)
  - A-E, 1980 (Box 26)
  - E-I, 1980 (Box 27)
  - I-M, 1980 (Box 28)
  - N-V, 1980 (Box 29)
  - Water Control Board, 1980 (Box 30)
  - Appalachian Regional Commission, 1980 (Box 31)
  - Budget, etc., 1980 (Box 32)
  - A-C, 1981 (Box 33)
  - C-D, 1981 (Box 34)
  - E-H, 1981 (Box 35)
  - H-N, 1981 (Box 36)
  - N-V, 1981 (Box 37)
  - W, Bud Long's Reports, 1981 (Box 38)
  - Bud Long's Reports, Memos to Agencies, 1981 (Box 39)
  - Misc., 1981 (Box 40)
- Series IV: Correspondence and subject files, [Accession 32269], 1980-1984, Extent: 17 cu. ft. (17 boxes). (Box 1-17)
  - Budget materials, 1980-1984 (Box 1)
  - A, 1982-1983 (Box 2-3)
  - A-95 Grievance, 1982-1983 (Box 4)
  - B-C, 1982-1983 (Box 5)
  - C, 1982-1983 (Box 6)
  - Cabinet memos, 1982-1983 (Box 7)
  - Comp-Environment, 1982-1983 (Box 8)
  - Florida-Gunston, 1982-1983 (Box 9)
  - Hampton-Memos, 1982-1983 (Box 10)
  - Historic-Jobs, 1982-1983 (Box 11)
  - Labor-Marine, 1982-1983 (Box 12)
  - Member-National, 1982-1983 (Box 13)
  - Museum-Trade, 1982-1983 (Box 14)
  - National-Private, 1982-1983 (Box 15)
  - Public-Telecom, 1982-1983 (Box 16)
  - United-Water, 1982-1983 (Box 17)
- Series V: Correspondence and subject files, [Accession 32511], 1982-1983, Extent: 19 cu. ft. (19 boxes). (Box 1-19)
  - Agriculture-Commodities Conditions, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - Air Board-Game & Inland Fisheries, 1982-1983 (Box 2)
  - Forestry-Economic Development Proposals, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
  - Chesapeake Bay, 1982-1983 (Box 4)
  - False Cape State Park, 1982-1983 (Box 5)
  - Div. Mine Land Reclamation-Governor's Job Training, 1982-1983 (Box 6)
  - Employment Commission, 1982-1983 (Box 7)
  - Council on the Environment-Outer Continental Shelf, 1982-1983 (Box 8)
  - Commission on Va. Future-Housing Development Authority, 1982-1983 (Box 9)
  - Industrial Development, 1982-1983 (Box 10)
  - International Trade-Labor & Industry, 1982-1983 (Box 11)
  - Marine Resources-Minority Business Enterprise, 1982-1983 (Box 12)
  - Reorganization of State Government-Va/MD Bi-State Committee, 1982-1983 (Box 13)
  - Uranium, 1982-1983 (Box 14)
  - Lake Gaston Environment Report, 1982-1983 (Box 15)
  - State Water Control Board, 1982-1983 (Box 16)
  - WHIM Tourism, 1982-1983 (Box 17)
  - Industrial Development/Gov's Euro Trip-Agriculture Work Plan, 1982-1983 (Box 18)
  - JLARC Seafood Report-Program Exhibits, 1982-1983 (Box 19)
- Series VI: Correspondence and subject files, [Accession 32673], 1984, Extent: 10 cu. ft. (10 boxes). (Box 1-10)
  - Agriculture, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture and Consumer Services, General, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture Product Commissions, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Animal Health, Division of, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Avian Flu, Indemnity payments, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Avian Flu, General quarantine, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Cattle Industry Commission, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Consumer Affairs Office, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Ethylene Diabromide, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Gypsy Moth Education Program, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Horse Center, 1984 (Box 1)
  - International Trade, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Markets, Division of, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Planning and Development, Division of, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Plant protection and Pesticide Regulation Bureau, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Wine and Grape Industry, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Air Pollution Control Board, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Acid Rain, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Clean Air Act, EPA (Auto Emissions, Emission Standards), 1984 (Box 2)
  - Clean Air Act, Wilderness, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Commerce, Dept. of, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Commerce, Dept. of, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Conservation and Economic Development, Dept. of, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Energy, Division of, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Mined Land Reclamation, Division of, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Mines, Mineral and Energy, Documentation and Creation of, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Two-Acre Mining, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Caledon State Park, 1984 (Box 3)
  - False Cape State Park, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Forestry, Division of, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Green Springs (Louisa County, Va.), 1984 (Box 4)
  - Litter Control, Division of, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Parks and Recreation, Division of, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Smith Mountain Lake Campground, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Tourism, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Advertising Information, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Exciting Times, Every Time, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Governor's Travel Advisory Committee, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Hampton Roads, Future of, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Southern Center for International Studies, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Tourism, General, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Travel Information, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Virginia is for Lovers, 1984 (Box 5)
  - We Have It Made in Virginia, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Wine Country Tours, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Dislocated workers, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Employment Commission, General, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Governor's Job Training Coordination Council, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Job Services, Division of, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Labor Market figures and reports, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Recruit, EEO, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Unemployment Insurance, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Veterans, Employment of, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Workman's Compensation, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Council on the Environment, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Bush River Watershed Site 12 Project, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Chesapeake Commission, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Chesapeake Bay Executive Council, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Chesapeake Bay conference report, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Coastal Zone Management, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Dioxin contamination, A.P. Hill, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Empress II, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Environmental Impact Statements, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Environment, Council on the, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Environmental Protection Agency, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Kepone, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Marine Sanctuary Program, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Outer Continental Shelf activities, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Uranium, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Chesapeake Bay Executive Council, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Chesapeake Bay, General, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Chesapeake Bay Initiatives, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Chesapeake Bay, Ruckelshaus Tour, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Fuel Conversion Authority, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Boating Advisory Committee, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Game and Inland Fisheries, Commission of, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Gunston Hall, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Historic Landmarks Commission, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Housing and Community Development, Office of, 1984 (Box 9)
  - Housing for Disabled, 1984 (Box 9)
  - Urban Enterprise Zones, 1984 (Box 9)
  - Housing Development Authority, 1984 (Box 9)
  - Community and Business Services, 1984 (Box 9)
  - Economic Development, General, 1984 (Box 9)
  - Innovative Technology, Center for, 1984 (Box 9)
  - International Marketing Efforts, 1984 (Box 9)
  - Marketing Companies in Virginia, 1984 (Box 9)
  - Marketing, High-tech, 1984 (Box 9)
  - Project Leapfrog, 1984 (Box 9)
  - Small Business and Financial Services, 1984 (Box 10)
  - Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation, 1984 (Box 10)
  - Dan River Mills, Cotton Dust, 1984 (Box 10)
  - Governor's Advisory Commission on Mine Safety, 1984 (Box 10)
  - Labor and Industry, Dept. of, 1984 (Box 10)